



"Success is the sum of small efforts repeated day in and day out."
- Robert Collier

## **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

My passion began many years ago with web design and evolved into a curiosity for how to "build stuff". I love being immersed in the programming world and am seeking a Junior Developer or internship opportunity. I am dedicated to learning my craft and would love to contribute to a team while building upon my current skill set.

Skills include:

Full-Stack Web Development, Object-Oriented Programming / Test Driven Development / Digital Project Management / Online Marketing Collateral / Graphic Design

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Ruby, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Software / Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, Middleman, WordPress, Photoshop

## **EDUCATION**

The Firehose Project, 2015

Full-Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails

Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY, 2003-2007

Martin J. Whitman School of Management

Bachelor of Science; Entrepreneurship & Emerging Enterprises

Dean's List

# **EXPERIENCE**

The Firehose Project, Remote, June 2015 - Present

# **Full-Stack Web Developer Apprentice**

Build web applications using Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, Test Driven Development, Git, GitHub, AWS, and Heroku. Solve Ruby coding challenges (algorithms and data structures).

Biz Dev Now, Remote, March 2014 - Present

### **Digital Project Manager**

Manage web development, graphic design and digital marketing projects from set-up to delivery for Biz Dev Now and it's clients; Source and hire freelancers. Expert WordPress set-up and maintenance. Graphic asset creation skills.

SmartsiteMovement, Aug 2012 - Sep 2014

#### Founder

Mobile -friendly websites for small businesses.

### Market Analyst

Progressive Business Publications, Malvern, PA, Feb 2011 - Sep 2012

Manage email marketing campaigns for Fortune 500 to mid-sized companies. Revise marketing copy for struggling email marketing campaigns to improve lead generation results. Design landing pages and conduct newsletter updates on WordPress site.

FedSources, Washington, DC Metro, 2010 - 2011

# Market Intelligence Analyst

Analyze and track federal government opportunities released by U.S. Navy agencies. Conduct in-depth internet and primary research for clients. Build professional relationships with Navy Contracting Officers. Attend industry conferences and publish reports for company website.

Help Unlimited Temps & Office Team, Washington, DC Metro, 2008 - 2009

## **Administrative Assistant**

Temp Assignments:

DC Housing Finance Agency

Provide assistance to public regarding real estate buyer program and admin support to agency.

Giuliani Associates Architects Inc.

Data entry, AP/AR, payroll assistance, project folder maintenance

ComputerTraining.com, Newark, DE, 2007 - 2008

# **Assistant Director of Admissions**

Manage email marketing campaigns for Fortune 500 to mid-sized companies. Revise marketing copy for struggling email marketing campaigns to improve lead generation results. Design landing pages and conduct newsletter updates on WordPress site.